Guide to the Tom Rankin photographs and papers, 1977-2016 RL.10043
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographs from China, 2016; 34 prints 3 boxes
  - Drying grain on the road, Kunshan, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0139)
    道路上晒的粮食，昆山市
  - Boats tied along Zhang Xin Dyke River, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0140)
    张新塘水边拴着的船
  - Garden and apartment building, Kunshan, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0141)
    花园和公寓，昆山市
  - Faux old bridge at abandoned theme park, Kunshan, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0142)
    废弃的主题公园里的人工桥，昆山市
  - Fields, farmer and canal, near DKU, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0143)
    农田，农夫和运河，昆山杜克大学校园附近
  - Giant crab sign and flagpole, 2016 (Box 27, Image RL.10043-P-0144)
    旗杆上的大螃蟹标志
  - Candles burning at shrine, Zhang Xin Dyke, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 28, Image RL.10043-P-0145)
    20x24 inch print
    庙里燃烧的蜡烛，张新塘，巴城镇
  - View of temple and river from bridge, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 28, Image RL.10043-P-0146)
    从桥上看寺庙和河流，巴城镇
  - Fish market, Bacheng, 2016 (Box 28, Image RL.10043-P-0147)
    鱼市，巴城镇
- Other Photographic Work, 2001; 4
  Series houses a gelatin silver 11x14 inch print of North Carolina author Tim McLaurin. Original title supplied by photographer.
  - Tim McLaurin at home with George, African Spur Foot Tortoise, Hillsborough, North Carolina, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 2, Image RL-10043-P-0113)
- Manuscripts and Recordings, circa 1980-2013; 14 boxes, 1 mp3 file
  Scope and Contents note
  Professional papers, including correspondence, writings, teaching materials, and other documents, stemming from Tom Rankin's long career in teaching and documentary arts, and serving as Director of the Center for Documentary Studies at Duke University. Includes a digital audio recording of his opening talk on February 27, 2008 at the Duke University Libraries exhibit of his work, Near the Cross: Photographs from the Mississippi Delta. This file has been mounted on the library server and is also available online through the Duke Libraries digital exhibits website. The papers have been given basic processing.
  - Professional files and recordings, circa 1980-2013 (Box 10-25)
- Other Audiovisual Materials, 1977, 1985; 2 items
  - Four Women Artists, 1977
    Directed by Bill Ferris and produced by Judy Peiser, Center for Southern Folklore, 1977.
    - 16mm screening print, color, optical sound, 1977; 850 film feet; Color faded. (Box AV 1, Film-reel RL10034-16mm-0001)
  - Dance Like a River: ODADAA! Drumming and Dancing in the U.S., 1985
    Directed and produced by Barry Dorfeld and Tom Rankin, Oboade Institute for African Culture, 1985.
    - 16mm screening print, color, optical sound, 1985; 1500 film feet (Box AV 1, Film-reel RL10034-16mm-0002)